https://www.crisisnavigator.com/Privacy.privacy.0.html

NewsletterMediaSitemapContactPrivacyImprint
Crisis InformationCrisis ResearchCrisis ConsultingCrisis TrainingAbout usOverviewEmergency CallMediaNewsletterContactPrivacyImprintSitemapSearchEmergency Call
Privacy Policy
Preamble
The aim of this privacy policy is, in accordance with the provisions of Articles 12, 13 and 14 of the General Data Protection Regulation (DSGVO), information on the nature, purpose and scope of the collection and processing of personal data within our website (website, social media profiles, e-mail Server etc.). The terms used here are based on the definitions in Art. 4 DSGVO.
§ 1 - Name and address of the person responsible
The person responsible within the meaning of the General Data Protection Regulation (DSGVO) and other national data protection laws of the member states as well as other data protection regulations is:
Crisisnavigator - Institute for Crisis Research A spin-off of the University of Kiel Managing Director: Frank Roselieb VAT-ID-Number: DE222282377 Schauenburgerstrasse 116 D-24118 Kiel, Germany Phone: +49 (0)431 907 - 26 10 Fax: +49 (0)431 907 - 26 11 Internet: www.crisisnavigator.com E-Mail: headoffice@crisisnavigator.com
Inquiries regarding data protection should be directed to the above mentioned address with the subject "Privacy Policy".
§ 2 - General information about data processing
In principle, we process personal data of our users only insofar as this is necessary to provide a functioning website and our content and services. The processing of personal data of our users takes place regularly only with the consent of the user. An exception applies to cases in which prior consent can not be obtained for reasons of fact and the processing of the data is permitted by law.
Insofar as we obtain the consent of the data subject for processing of personal data, Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) as legal basis. In the processing of personal data necessary for the performance of a contract to which the data subject is a party, Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b DSGVO as legal basis. This also applies to processing operations required to carry out pre-contractual actions.
Insofar as processing of personal data is required to fulfill a legal obligation that is subject to our company or association, Art. 6 para. 1 lit. c DSGVO as legal basis. In the event that vital interests of the data subject or another natural person require the processing of personal data, Art. 6 para. 1 lit. d DSGVO as legal basis.
If processing is necessary to safeguard the legitimate interests of our company or association or a third party, and if the interest, fundamental rights and fundamental freedoms of the data subject do not prevail over the first interest, Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f DSGVO as legal basis for processing.
The personal data of the data subject will be deleted or blocked as soon as the purpose of the storage is deleted. In addition, such storage may be provided for by the European or national legislator in EU regulations, laws or other regulations to which the controller is subject. Blocking or deletion of the data also takes place when a storage period prescribed by the standards mentioned expires, unless there is a need for further storage of the data for conclusion of a contract or fulfillment of the contract.
In order to protect data against deliberate or unconscious manipulation, spying or access by third parties, loss or annihilation, we use a variety of security mechanisms of a technical and organizational nature. The website uses the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption method for the transmission of data. The respective encryption level is determined by the user's browser. Typically, 256-bit encryption is used. If the browser does not support this level, 128-bit encryption will be used instead. The user recognizes the encryption on the lock symbol in the status or navigation bar as well as on the "https: //" in the address bar of the browser.
§ 3 - Rights of the person concerned
If personal data is processed by you, you are the person concerned within the meaning of the DSGVO and you have the following rights towards the responsible person:
1. Right to information
You may ask the person in charge to confirm if personal data concerning you is processed by us. If such processing is available, you can request information from the person responsible about the following information: (1) the purposes for which the personal data are processed; (2) the categories of personal data being processed; (3) the recipients or categories of recipients to whom the personal data relating to you have been disclosed or are still being disclosed; (4) the planned duration of the storage of your personal data or, if specific information is not available, criteria for determining the duration of storage; (5) the existence of a right to rectification or erasure of personal data concerning you, a right to restriction of processing by the controller or a right to object to such processing; (6) the existence of a right of appeal to a supervisory authority; (7) all available information on the source of the data if the personal data is not collected from the data subject; (8) the existence of automated decision-making including profiling under Article 22 (1) and (4) GDPR and, at least in these cases, meaningful information about the logic involved, and the scope and intended impact of such processing on the data subject. You have the right to request information about whether your personal information relates to a third country or an international organization. In this connection, you can request the appropriate guarantees in accordance with. Art. 46 GDPR in connection with the transfer. This right of access may be limited to the extent that it is likely to render impossible or seriously affect the realization of the research or statistical purposes and the restriction is necessary for the performance of the research or statistical purposes.
2. Right to rectification
You have a right to rectification and / or completion to the controller, if the personal data you process is incorrect or incomplete. The responsible person must make the correction without delay. Its right of rectification may be limited to the extent that it is likely to render impossible or seriously affect the realization of research or statistical purposes and the restriction is necessary for the performance of research or statistical purposes.
3. Right to restriction of processing
You may request the restriction of the processing of your personal data under the following conditions: (1) if you contest the accuracy of your personal information for a period of time that enables the controller to verify the accuracy of your personal information; (2) the processing is unlawful and you refuse the deletion of the personal data and instead demand the restriction of the use of the personal data; (3) the controller no longer needs the personal data for the purposes of processing, but you need it to assert, exercise or defend legal claims; or (4) if you have objected to the processing pursuant to Art. 21 (1) GDPR and it is not yet certain whether the legitimate reasons of the person responsible outweigh your reasons. If the processing of personal data concerning you has been restricted, this data may only be used with your consent or for the purpose of asserting, exercising or defending legal claims or protecting the rights of another natural or legal person or for reasons of important public interest Union or a Member State.
If the restriction on processing has been restricted in accordance with the above conditions, the person responsible will inform you before the restriction is lifted. Its right to restriction of processing may be restricted to the extent that it is likely to render impossible or seriously affect the realization of the research or statistical purposes and the restriction is necessary for the performance of the research or statistical purposes.
4. Right to cancellation
(a) Obligation to delete
You may require the controller to delete your personal information without delay, and the controller is required to delete that information immediately if one of the following is true: (1) Personal data concerning you are no longer necessary for the purposes for which they were collected or otherwise processed. (2) You revoke your consent, to which the processing acc. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a or Art. 9 para. 2 lit. DSGVO and there is no other legal basis for processing. (3) According to. Art. 21 para. 1 DSGVO objection to the processing and there are no prior justifiable reasons for the processing, or you lay gem. Art. 21 para. 2 DSGVO Opposition to processing. (4) Your personal data have been processed unlawfully. (5) The deletion of personal data concerning you shall be required to fulfill a legal obligation under Union law or the law of the Member States to which the controller is subject. (6) The personal data concerning you were collected in relation to information society services offered pursuant to Art. 8 (1) GDPR. (b) information to third parties
If the person in charge has made the personal data concerning you public and is acc. Article 17 (1) of the GDPR, it shall take appropriate measures, including technical means, to inform data controllers who process the personal data that you have been identified as being affected, taking into account available technology and implementation costs Persons requesting deletion of all links to such personal data or of copies or replications of such personal data.
(c) Exceptions
The right to erasure does not exist if the processing is necessary (1) to exercise the right to freedom of expression and information; (2) to fulfill a legal obligation required by the law of the Union or of the Member States to which the controller is subject, or to carry out a task which is in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority conferring on the controller has been; (3) for reasons of public interest in the field of public health pursuant to Art. 9 (2) lit. h and i and Art. 9 (3) GDPR; (4) for archival purposes of public interest, scientific or historical research purposes or for statistical purposes acc. Article 89 (1) GDPR, to the extent that the law referred to in subparagraph (a) is likely to render impossible or seriously affect the achievement of the objectives of that processing, or (5) to assert, exercise or defend legal claims. 5. Right to information
If you have the right of rectification, erasure or restriction of processing to the controller, he / she is obliged to notify all recipients to whom your personal data have been disclosed of this correction or deletion of the data or restriction of processing, unless: this proves to be impossible or involves a disproportionate effort. You have a right to the person responsible to be informed about these recipients.
6. Right to Data Portability
You have the right to receive personally identifiable information you provide to the controller in a structured, common and machine-readable format. In addition, you have the right to transfer this data to another person without hindrance by the person responsible for providing the personal data, provided that (1) the processing on a consent acc. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR or Art. 9 para. 2 lit. a DSGVO or on a contract acc. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b DSGVO is based and (2) the processing is done by automated means. In exercising this right, you also have the right to obtain that your personal data relating to you are transmitted directly from one person to another, insofar as this is technically feasible. Freedoms and rights of other persons may not be affected. The right to data portability does not apply to the processing of personal data necessary for the performance of a task in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority delegated to the controller.
7. Right to object
You have the right at any time, for reasons that arise from your particular situation, against the processing of your personal data, which pursuant to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. e or f DSGVO takes an objection; this also applies to profiling based on these provisions. The controller will no longer process the personal data relating to you unless he can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for processing that outweigh your interests, rights and freedoms, or the processing is intended to assert, exercise or defend legal claims. If the personal data relating to you are processed for direct marketing purposes, you have the right to object at any time to the processing of your personal data for the purpose of such advertising; this also applies to profiling insofar as it is associated with such direct mail.
If you object to processing for direct marketing purposes, your personal data will no longer be processed for these purposes. Regardless of Directive 2002/58 / EC, you have the option, in the context of the use of information society services, of exercising your right to object through automated procedures that use technical specifications. You also have the right, for reasons that arise from your particular situation, in processing personal data relating to you for scientific or historical research purposes or for statistical purposes. Art. 89 para. 1 GDPR is to be contradicted.
Its right of objection may be limited to the extent that it is likely to render impossible or seriously affect the realization of the research or statistical purposes, and that the restriction is necessary for the performance of the research or statistical purposes.
8. Right to revoke the data protection consent declaration
You have the right to revoke your data protection declaration at any time. The revocation of consent does not affect the legality of the processing carried out on the basis of the consent until the revocation.
9. Automated decision on a case-by-case basis, including profiling
You have the right not to be subjected to a decision based solely on automated processing - including profiling - that will have legal effect or similarly affect you in a similar manner. This does not apply if the decision (1) is required for the conclusion or performance of a contract between you and the controller, (2) is permitted by Union or Member State legislation to which the controller is subject, and where such legislation contains appropriate measures to safeguard your rights and freedoms and legitimate interests, or (3) with your express consent. However, these decisions must not be based on special categories of personal data under Art. 9 (1) GDPR, unless Art. 9 (2) lit. a or g DSGVO applies and reasonable measures have been taken to protect the rights and freedoms as well as your legitimate interests. With regard to the cases referred to in (1) and (3), the person responsible shall take appropriate measures to uphold the rights and freedoms and their legitimate interests, including at least the right to obtain the intervention of a person by the controller, to express his / her own position and heard on challenge of the decision.
10. Right to complain to a supervisory authority
Without prejudice to any other administrative or judicial remedy, you shall have the right to complain to a supervisory authority, in particular in the Member State of its residence, place of work or place of alleged infringement, if you believe that the processing of the personal data concerning you is against the DSGVO violates. The supervisory authority to which the complaint has been submitted shall inform the complainant of the status and results of the complaint, including the possibility of a judicial remedy pursuant to Article 78 of the GDPR. The contact details of the responsible data protection officer are available on the following website: [https://www.bfdi.bund.de/DE/Infothek/Anschriften_Links/anschriften_links-node.html - as of May 2018].
§ 4 - Website and Logfiles
Each time our website is accessed, our system automatically collects data and information from the computer system of the calling computer. The following data is collected: (1) information about the browser type and the version used, (2) the user's operating system, (3) the user's Internet service provider, (4) the user's IP address, (5 ) Date and time of access, (6) websites from which the user's system accesses our website, (7) websites accessed by the user's system via our website.
The data is also stored in the log files of our system. A storage of this data together with other personal data of the user does not take place. The legal basis for the temporary storage of data and log files is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f DSGVO. The temporary storage of the IP address by the system is necessary to allow delivery of the website to the computer of the user. To do this, the user's IP address must be kept for the duration of the session.
Storage in log files is done to ensure the functionality of the website. In addition, the data is used to optimize the website and to ensure the security of our information technology systems. An evaluation of the data for marketing purposes does not take place in this context. For these purposes, our legitimate interest in the processing of data according to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f DSGVO. The data will be deleted as soon as it is no longer necessary for the purpose of its collection. In the case of collecting the data for providing the website, this is the case when the respective session is completed.
In the case of storing the data in log files, this is the case after no more than seven days. An additional storage is possible. In this case, the IP addresses of the users are deleted or alienated, so that an assignment of the calling client is no longer possible. The collection of data for the provision of the website and the storage of the data in log files is essential for the operation of the website. There is consequently no contradiction on the part of the user.
§ 5 - Cookies
Our website uses cookies. Cookies are text files that are stored in the Internet browser or the Internet browser on the user's computer system. When a user visits a website, a cookie may be stored on the user's operating system. This cookie contains a characteristic string that allows the browser to be uniquely identified when the website is reopened. We use cookies to make our website more user-friendly. Some elements of our website require that the calling browser be identified even after a page break. The following data is stored and transmitted in the cookies: language settings and log-in information.
The legal basis for the processing of personal data using cookies is Article 6 (1) lit. f DSGVO. The purpose of using technically necessary cookies is to facilitate the use of websites for users. Some features of our website can not be offered without the use of cookies. For these, it is necessary that the browser is recognized even after a page break. We require cookies for the following applications: (1) adopting language settings, (2) remembering search terms. The user data collected through technically necessary cookies will not be used to create user profiles. For these purposes, our legitimate interest in the processing of personal data pursuant to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f DSGVO.
Cookies are stored on the computer of the user and transmitted by this on our side. Therefore, as a user, you have full control over the use of cookies. By changing the settings in your internet browser, you can disable or restrict the transmission of cookies. Already saved cookies can be deleted at any time. This can also be done automatically. If cookies are disabled for our website, it may not be possible to use all the functions of the website to the full. The transmission of Flash cookies can not be prevented by the settings of the browser, but by changing the settings of the Flash Player.
§ 6 - Newsletter
On our website you can subscribe to a free newsletter. When registering for the newsletter, the following data will be sent to us: E-mail address of the user, IP address of the calling computer, date and time of registration. For the processing of the data, your consent is obtained during the registration process and reference is made to this privacy policy.
If you purchase goods or services on our website and deposit your e-mail address here, this can subsequently be used by us to send a newsletter. In such a case, the newsletter will only send direct mail for your own similar goods or services. In connection with the processing of data for the sending of newsletters, there is no disclosure of the data to third parties. The data will be used exclusively for sending the newsletter.
The legal basis for the processing of the data after the user has registered for the newsletter is the consent of the user Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR. The legal basis for sending the newsletter as a result of the sale of goods or services is § 7 Abs. 3 UWG. The collection of the user's e-mail address serves to deliver the newsletter. The collection of other personal data in the context of the registration process serves to prevent misuse of the services or the email address used.
The data will be deleted as soon as it is no longer necessary for the purpose of its collection. The e-mail address of the user is therefore stored as long as the subscription to the newsletter is active. The other personal data collected during the registration process will normally be deleted after a period of seven days. Subscription to the newsletter may be terminated at any time by the user concerned. For this purpose, there is a corresponding link in each newsletter. This also allows a revocation of the consent to the storage of the personal data collected during the registration process.
§ 7 - Registration
On our website, we offer users the opportunity to register by providing personal information. The data is entered into an input mask and transmitted to us and stored. A transfer of data to third parties does not take place. The following data is collected during the registration process: title, first name, surname, birth date if applicable, place of birth, company, department, address, phone, if necessary fax, e-mail, internet address if applicable.
At the time of registration, the following data is also stored: The IP address of the user, date and time of registration. As part of the registration process, the consent of the user to process this data is obtained. Legal basis for the processing of the data is in the presence of the consent of the user Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR. If the registration serves the fulfillment of a contract of which the user is a party or the implementation of pre-contractual measures, an additional legal basis for the processing of the data is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b DSGVO.
User registration is required for the provision of certain content and services on our website, such as password-protected areas for specific user groups. Registration of the user is also required to fulfill a contract with the user or to perform pre-contractual action - for example, membership, attendance, training and consulting.
The data will be deleted as soon as it is no longer necessary for the purpose of its collection. On the one hand, this is the case for the data collected during the registration process, when the registration on our website is canceled or modified. On the other hand, this is the case during the registration process for the performance of a contract or the performance of pre-contractual measures when the data is no longer necessary for the performance of the contract. Even after the conclusion of the contract, there may be a need to store personal data of the contracting party in order to comply with contractual or legal obligations.
As a user, you have the option of canceling the registration at any time. You can change the data stored about you at any time. Please contact the above mentioned office. If the data is required to fulfill a contract or to carry out pre-contractual measures, premature deletion of the data is only possible, unless contractual or legal obligations preclude deletion.
§ 8 - contact form and e-mail contact
On our website is a contact form available, which can be used for electronic contact. If a user realizes this option, the data entered in the input mask will be transmitted to us and saved. These data include: Title, first and last name, address, telephone, fax, e-mail, Internet address.
At the time of sending the message, the following data is also stored: (1) the user's IP address, (2) date and time of registration. For the processing of the data in the context of the sending process your consent is obtained and referred to this privacy statement. Alternatively, contact via the provided e-mail address is possible. In this case, the user's personal data transmitted by e-mail will be stored.
In this context, there is no disclosure of the data to third parties. The data is used exclusively for processing the conversation. Legal basis for the processing of the data is in the presence of the consent of the user Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR. The legal basis for the processing of the data transmitted in the course of sending an e-mail is Article 6 (1) lit. f DSGVO. If the e-mail contact aims to conclude a contract, then additional legal basis for the processing is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b DSGVO.
The processing of the personal data from the input mask serves us only to process the contact. In the case of contact via e-mail, this also includes the required legitimate interest in the processing of the data. The other personal data processed during the sending process serve to prevent misuse of the contact form and to ensure the security of our information technology systems.
The data will be deleted as soon as it is no longer necessary for the purpose of its collection. For the personal data from the input form of the contact form and those sent by e-mail, this is the case when the respective conversation with the user has ended. The conversation is ended when it can be inferred from the circumstances that the relevant facts have been finally clarified. The additional personal data collected during the sending process will be deleted at the latest after a period of seven days.
The user has the possibility at any time to revoke his consent to the processing of the personal data. If the user contacts us by e-mail, he may object to the storage of his personal data at any time. In such a case, the conversation can not continue. Please contact the above mentioned office for this purpose. All personal data stored in the course of contacting will be deleted in this case.
§ 9 - Google
We use Google Adwords Conversion Tracking to statistically track the use of our website. If the user has reached this website via an advertisement on Google, Google places a cookie on the user's computer. The cookie can not be used to personally identify users and will expire after 30 days. Google uses the cookies to generate conversion statistics. These tell Adwords customers how many people have been redirected to the site through the ad. Information for the personal identification of users is not included.
If users do not want to participate in the Google Adwords Conversion Tracking, you can set their browser individually so that cookies from the Internet address www.googleadservices.com are not accepted. Alternatively, the setting of cookies can be completely blocked by a corresponding browser setting. For more information about Google Adwords Conversion Tracking privacy, visit the following Internet address [https://services.google.com/sitestats/en.html - as of May 2018].
We use Google Analytics to obtain information for the continuous optimization of this website. For this purpose, Google places a cookie on the user's computer and creates usage profiles in pseudonymised form. The following information is collected by Google in connection with the cookie and stored on servers in the USA: Type and version of the browser, operating system used, URL of the previously visited page, IP address or host name of the accessing computer, date and time of the server request.
Google uses this information to compile reports on the use of the website in anonymous form for the purposes of market and usage research. The owner of the website is thus given the opportunity to make the website needs-based. Google also transmits this data to third parties, provided that they process the data in the order or the transfer is required by law. In the context of IP masking, the IP addresses are anonymized, so that an assignment of the data to specific persons is not possible.
If users so wish, they can prevent the placement of a cookie or the processing of the data collected by Google. For this purpose, you must either install the relevant browser add-on or set a temporary opt-out cookie by clicking on the website [https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en - as of May 2018]. However, the opt-out cookie in question only applies to the website in question only in the browser in question. If the cookie is deleted when closing the browser or manually, it must be reset. Alternatively, the setting of cookies can be completely blocked by a corresponding browser setting. Additional information on Google Analytics privacy can be found at the following Internet address [https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en - as of May 2018].
We integrate Google Maps as maps to give users a spatial orientation (eg for the journey). Google places a cookie on the user's computer in order to process the user settings in this way. Google processes the IP address of the user as well as his location data and stores them on servers in the USA.
Users who do not want Google to process and store this data can prevent this through individual settings on their mobile phone, notebook etc. For this purpose, the function "Java Script" must be deactivated in the browser. Then, however, no use of the maps is possible. More information on Google Maps privacy can be found on the following Internet address [https://www.google.com/intl/en_en/help/terms_maps.html - as of May 2018].
We use Google Fonts as fonts on the website to make the content visually appealing and technically sound. When you call the font library, your browser connects to the publisher of the font library. In doing so, the provider may collect your IP address and browser type and store that data on servers in the United States. The font library is also transferred to the cache of your browser so that it does not have to be loaded multiple times by the server.
Users who do not want to display using Google Fonts can opt-out from the following page: [https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated - as of May 2018]. Additional Google information on Google Fonts privacy can be found at the following Internet address [https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en - as of May 2018]. The company can be reached as follows (as of May 2018): Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA.§ 10 - Social Media Plug-ins
On our website, we use social plug-ins from the three social networks Facebook, Twitter and Google+. Integration uses the two-click method to best protect site users. The legal basis is Art. 6 para. 1 sentence 1 lit. f DSGVO and the purpose of advertising or publicizing our website in the social media. The legal responsibility for the operation according to the data protection regulations lies with the respective providers. You can reach the providers as follows (as of May 2018): Facebook, Inc., 1601 Willow Road, Menlo Park, CA 94025, USA, Twitter, Inc., 1355 Market Street, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, United States Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. When a user opens a website with a personalized social plug-in, the browser connects to the social network servers in the US and stores information there. This transmits the IP address and URL of the page in question to the networks. If the user is currently logged in to his social network account, the networks also assign the visit to the website directly to the relevant user account.
If the user interacts with the individually activated social plug-in (eg "Share", "Like"), this information is also transmitted to the servers of the social networks and stored there. The social networks also publish the information in the profile of the respective user or inform the respective friends, followers, etc. In addition, the social networks use the information for the purpose of their own page optimization and user profiling (eg in the display of matching advertisements).
If users wish to prevent their information from being passed on to the social networks or their activities on our site are linked to their user accounts, they must log out of their social network user accounts before visiting this site and participate in the social plug-in do not enable the two-click method.
We operate presences on the social networks Facebook, Twitter and Google+ to communicate information about our services and to interact with users. If users compose posts within our presence on the social networks or use them to send messages to us, we process them in accordance with this privacy policy. In addition, when calling and using the social networks, the data processing declarations of the respective operators apply.
As a provider of the website, we generally do not receive any information about the content of the data transmitted to the social networks or the further use by the social networks. For information on the extent and purpose of data collection, data processing and data use by the social networks, users should therefore read the relevant data protection notice of Facebook [https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy - as of May 2018], Twitter [ https://twitter.com/privacy - as of May 2018] and Google [https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en - as of May 2018].
§ 11 - Amazon
We are affiliates of Amazon Affiliate Program. By making links from this website to Amazon.de, advertising reimbursements are earned. This serves the purpose of enabling us to economically operate the website. Amazon places cookies on the computer of the user. This will allow Amazon to tell which website from which IP address which link was clicked, and then possibly purchase a product from Amazon. Users who do not want this data transmission to Amazon can prevent this by not clicking on the relevant link to Amazon.de. Further information from Amazon on privacy can be found at the following Internet address [https://www.amazon.de/gp/help/customer/display.html?nodeId=3312401 - as of May 2018]. The company can be reached as follows: Amazon Europe Core S.à.rl, 5 Rue Plaetis, L-2338 Luxembourg.§ 12 - Applicants
Applicants will provide us with necessary data for the application process. The data transmitted here result from the job description. This usually includes personal information (eg contact addresses), motivation (eg cover letter) and previous career (eg CV, certificates). Applicants are free to submit further information. If the applicant submits special categories of personal data (eg, severe disability), the data processing is additionally carried out in accordance with Art. 9 (2) lit. b DSGVO.
The information provided by the applicant is intended to enable us to fulfill our obligations under the application procedure. Data collection and data processing are carried out in accordance with Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b. DSGVO and Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f. DSGVO and the use of the transmitted data exclusively in the context of the application process. When submitting by e-mail, the applicant himself has to provide adequate encryption. If this is not possible for him, he can submit the application by post.
If the application was successful, the data submitted by the applicant will be further processed and stored for the purposes of administration and billing of the employment relationship. If the application was unsuccessful or the application is withdrawn by the applicant, the data submitted by the applicant will be deleted. The time of deletion results from the proof duties of the general equal treatment law (AGG), is usually six months and is subject to a possibly justified cancellation of the applicants.
§ 13 - Customers or members
Via the website persons can conclude legally valid contracts for the use of paid services (eg attendance of events, membership in associations). For this purpose, the collection and processing of personal data of the contracting party in accordance with Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b DSGVO or Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f. DSGVO necessary (eg, first and last name, postal address, e-mail address, telephone number, services used, payment information). The IP address as well as the date and time of the conclusion of the contract by the user are also stored.
The purpose of the processing is the administration, provision and billing of corresponding services as well as the maintenance of our business operations. In part, the processing and storage of personal data is also based on statutory provisions (eg tax law), contractual provisions (eg delivery address, performance variant) or security reasons (eg to verify the ownership of e-mail addresses, seriousness of the desired receipt of service, accuracy the billing address).
A transfer of these data to third parties does not take place, as long as no legal obligation according to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. c DSGVO exists or this is necessary for the performance or enforcement of our claims. The data will be deleted as soon as they are no longer required for business or statutory purposes. The deletion point results from the legal storage obligations as well as from warranty or liability regulations. The need for further data storage is reviewed every three years.
§ 14 - Status and necessary changes
This Privacy Policy was created in May 2018. Due to the further development of our website and the further development of the law, changes to the privacy policy may become necessary. You will find the currently valid privacy policy here.
German
/  English
Last update: Friday, 11. December 2020
© Crisisnavigator - Institute for Crisis Research / Crisisnavigator Consulting, Kiel / Hamburg.
All rights reserved. No unauthorised reproduction or distribution - not even in extracts.
Internet: www.crisisnavigator.com
E-Mail: info@crisisnavigator.com
Newsletter    Media    Sitemap    Contact    Privacy    Imprint
A "spin-off" of the University of Kiel (Germany).
Volume 21 (2020) - Issue 12 (December) - ISSN 1619-2400
Crisis InformationCrisis ManagementCrisis CommunicationsIssues ManagementDisaster ManagementBusiness ContinuityContactCrisis ResearchOverviewContactCrisis ConsultingOverviewCrisis PreventionCrisis IdentificationCrisis ManagementCrisis RecoveryContactCrisis TrainingOverviewContactAbout usOverviewEmergency CallMediaNewsletterContactPrivacyImprintSitemapSearchEmergency Call
About us > Privacy
Privacy Policy
Preamble
The aim of this privacy policy is, in accordance with the provisions of Articles 12, 13 and 14 of the General Data Protection Regulation (DSGVO), information on the nature, purpose and scope of the collection and processing of personal data within our website (website, social media profiles, e-mail Server etc.). The terms used here are based on the definitions in Art. 4 DSGVO.
§ 1 - Name and address of the person responsible
The person responsible within the meaning of the General Data Protection Regulation (DSGVO) and other national data protection laws of the member states as well as other data protection regulations is:
Crisisnavigator - Institute for Crisis Research A spin-off of the University of Kiel Managing Director: Frank Roselieb VAT-ID-Number: DE222282377 Schauenburgerstrasse 116 D-24118 Kiel, Germany Phone: +49 (0)431 907 - 26 10 Fax: +49 (0)431 907 - 26 11 Internet: www.crisisnavigator.com E-Mail: headoffice@crisisnavigator.com
Inquiries regarding data protection should be directed to the above mentioned address with the subject "Privacy Policy".
§ 2 - General information about data processing
In principle, we process personal data of our users only insofar as this is necessary to provide a functioning website and our content and services. The processing of personal data of our users takes place regularly only with the consent of the user. An exception applies to cases in which prior consent can not be obtained for reasons of fact and the processing of the data is permitted by law.
Insofar as we obtain the consent of the data subject for processing of personal data, Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) as legal basis. In the processing of personal data necessary for the performance of a contract to which the data subject is a party, Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b DSGVO as legal basis. This also applies to processing operations required to carry out pre-contractual actions.
Insofar as processing of personal data is required to fulfill a legal obligation that is subject to our company or association, Art. 6 para. 1 lit. c DSGVO as legal basis. In the event that vital interests of the data subject or another natural person require the processing of personal data, Art. 6 para. 1 lit. d DSGVO as legal basis.
If processing is necessary to safeguard the legitimate interests of our company or association or a third party, and if the interest, fundamental rights and fundamental freedoms of the data subject do not prevail over the first interest, Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f DSGVO as legal basis for processing.
The personal data of the data subject will be deleted or blocked as soon as the purpose of the storage is deleted. In addition, such storage may be provided for by the European or national legislator in EU regulations, laws or other regulations to which the controller is subject. Blocking or deletion of the data also takes place when a storage period prescribed by the standards mentioned expires, unless there is a need for further storage of the data for conclusion of a contract or fulfillment of the contract.
In order to protect data against deliberate or unconscious manipulation, spying or access by third parties, loss or annihilation, we use a variety of security mechanisms of a technical and organizational nature. The website uses the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption method for the transmission of data. The respective encryption level is determined by the user's browser. Typically, 256-bit encryption is used. If the browser does not support this level, 128-bit encryption will be used instead. The user recognizes the encryption on the lock symbol in the status or navigation bar as well as on the "https: //" in the address bar of the browser.
§ 3 - Rights of the person concerned
If personal data is processed by you, you are the person concerned within the meaning of the DSGVO and you have the following rights towards the responsible person:
1. Right to information
You may ask the person in charge to confirm if personal data concerning you is processed by us. If such processing is available, you can request information from the person responsible about the following information: (1) the purposes for which the personal data are processed; (2) the categories of personal data being processed; (3) the recipients or categories of recipients to whom the personal data relating to you have been disclosed or are still being disclosed; (4) the planned duration of the storage of your personal data or, if specific information is not available, criteria for determining the duration of storage; (5) the existence of a right to rectification or erasure of personal data concerning you, a right to restriction of processing by the controller or a right to object to such processing; (6) the existence of a right of appeal to a supervisory authority; (7) all available information on the source of the data if the personal data is not collected from the data subject; (8) the existence of automated decision-making including profiling under Article 22 (1) and (4) GDPR and, at least in these cases, meaningful information about the logic involved, and the scope and intended impact of such processing on the data subject. You have the right to request information about whether your personal information relates to a third country or an international organization. In this connection, you can request the appropriate guarantees in accordance with. Art. 46 GDPR in connection with the transfer. This right of access may be limited to the extent that it is likely to render impossible or seriously affect the realization of the research or statistical purposes and the restriction is necessary for the performance of the research or statistical purposes.
2. Right to rectification
You have a right to rectification and / or completion to the controller, if the personal data you process is incorrect or incomplete. The responsible person must make the correction without delay. Its right of rectification may be limited to the extent that it is likely to render impossible or seriously affect the realization of research or statistical purposes and the restriction is necessary for the performance of research or statistical purposes.
3. Right to restriction of processing
You may request the restriction of the processing of your personal data under the following conditions: (1) if you contest the accuracy of your personal information for a period of time that enables the controller to verify the accuracy of your personal information; (2) the processing is unlawful and you refuse the deletion of the personal data and instead demand the restriction of the use of the personal data; (3) the controller no longer needs the personal data for the purposes of processing, but you need it to assert, exercise or defend legal claims; or (4) if you have objected to the processing pursuant to Art. 21 (1) GDPR and it is not yet certain whether the legitimate reasons of the person responsible outweigh your reasons. If the processing of personal data concerning you has been restricted, this data may only be used with your consent or for the purpose of asserting, exercising or defending legal claims or protecting the rights of another natural or legal person or for reasons of important public interest Union or a Member State.
If the restriction on processing has been restricted in accordance with the above conditions, the person responsible will inform you before the restriction is lifted. Its right to restriction of processing may be restricted to the extent that it is likely to render impossible or seriously affect the realization of the research or statistical purposes and the restriction is necessary for the performance of the research or statistical purposes.
4. Right to cancellation
(a) Obligation to delete
You may require the controller to delete your personal information without delay, and the controller is required to delete that information immediately if one of the following is true: (1) Personal data concerning you are no longer necessary for the purposes for which they were collected or otherwise processed. (2) You revoke your consent, to which the processing acc. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a or Art. 9 para. 2 lit. DSGVO and there is no other legal basis for processing. (3) According to. Art. 21 para. 1 DSGVO objection to the processing and there are no prior justifiable reasons for the processing, or you lay gem. Art. 21 para. 2 DSGVO Opposition to processing. (4) Your personal data have been processed unlawfully. (5) The deletion of personal data concerning you shall be required to fulfill a legal obligation under Union law or the law of the Member States to which the controller is subject. (6) The personal data concerning you were collected in relation to information society services offered pursuant to Art. 8 (1) GDPR. (b) information to third parties
If the person in charge has made the personal data concerning you public and is acc. Article 17 (1) of the GDPR, it shall take appropriate measures, including technical means, to inform data controllers who process the personal data that you have been identified as being affected, taking into account available technology and implementation costs Persons requesting deletion of all links to such personal data or of copies or replications of such personal data.
(c) Exceptions
The right to erasure does not exist if the processing is necessary (1) to exercise the right to freedom of expression and information; (2) to fulfill a legal obligation required by the law of the Union or of the Member States to which the controller is subject, or to carry out a task which is in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority conferring on the controller has been; (3) for reasons of public interest in the field of public health pursuant to Art. 9 (2) lit. h and i and Art. 9 (3) GDPR; (4) for archival purposes of public interest, scientific or historical research purposes or for statistical purposes acc. Article 89 (1) GDPR, to the extent that the law referred to in subparagraph (a) is likely to render impossible or seriously affect the achievement of the objectives of that processing, or (5) to assert, exercise or defend legal claims. 5. Right to information
If you have the right of rectification, erasure or restriction of processing to the controller, he / she is obliged to notify all recipients to whom your personal data have been disclosed of this correction or deletion of the data or restriction of processing, unless: this proves to be impossible or involves a disproportionate effort. You have a right to the person responsible to be informed about these recipients.
6. Right to Data Portability
You have the right to receive personally identifiable information you provide to the controller in a structured, common and machine-readable format. In addition, you have the right to transfer this data to another person without hindrance by the person responsible for providing the personal data, provided that (1) the processing on a consent acc. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR or Art. 9 para. 2 lit. a DSGVO or on a contract acc. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b DSGVO is based and (2) the processing is done by automated means. In exercising this right, you also have the right to obtain that your personal data relating to you are transmitted directly from one person to another, insofar as this is technically feasible. Freedoms and rights of other persons may not be affected. The right to data portability does not apply to the processing of personal data necessary for the performance of a task in the public interest or in the exercise of official authority delegated to the controller.
7. Right to object
You have the right at any time, for reasons that arise from your particular situation, against the processing of your personal data, which pursuant to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. e or f DSGVO takes an objection; this also applies to profiling based on these provisions. The controller will no longer process the personal data relating to you unless he can demonstrate compelling legitimate grounds for processing that outweigh your interests, rights and freedoms, or the processing is intended to assert, exercise or defend legal claims. If the personal data relating to you are processed for direct marketing purposes, you have the right to object at any time to the processing of your personal data for the purpose of such advertising; this also applies to profiling insofar as it is associated with such direct mail.
If you object to processing for direct marketing purposes, your personal data will no longer be processed for these purposes. Regardless of Directive 2002/58 / EC, you have the option, in the context of the use of information society services, of exercising your right to object through automated procedures that use technical specifications. You also have the right, for reasons that arise from your particular situation, in processing personal data relating to you for scientific or historical research purposes or for statistical purposes. Art. 89 para. 1 GDPR is to be contradicted.
Its right of objection may be limited to the extent that it is likely to render impossible or seriously affect the realization of the research or statistical purposes, and that the restriction is necessary for the performance of the research or statistical purposes.
8. Right to revoke the data protection consent declaration
You have the right to revoke your data protection declaration at any time. The revocation of consent does not affect the legality of the processing carried out on the basis of the consent until the revocation.
9. Automated decision on a case-by-case basis, including profiling
You have the right not to be subjected to a decision based solely on automated processing - including profiling - that will have legal effect or similarly affect you in a similar manner. This does not apply if the decision (1) is required for the conclusion or performance of a contract between you and the controller, (2) is permitted by Union or Member State legislation to which the controller is subject, and where such legislation contains appropriate measures to safeguard your rights and freedoms and legitimate interests, or (3) with your express consent. However, these decisions must not be based on special categories of personal data under Art. 9 (1) GDPR, unless Art. 9 (2) lit. a or g DSGVO applies and reasonable measures have been taken to protect the rights and freedoms as well as your legitimate interests. With regard to the cases referred to in (1) and (3), the person responsible shall take appropriate measures to uphold the rights and freedoms and their legitimate interests, including at least the right to obtain the intervention of a person by the controller, to express his / her own position and heard on challenge of the decision.
10. Right to complain to a supervisory authority
Without prejudice to any other administrative or judicial remedy, you shall have the right to complain to a supervisory authority, in particular in the Member State of its residence, place of work or place of alleged infringement, if you believe that the processing of the personal data concerning you is against the DSGVO violates. The supervisory authority to which the complaint has been submitted shall inform the complainant of the status and results of the complaint, including the possibility of a judicial remedy pursuant to Article 78 of the GDPR. The contact details of the responsible data protection officer are available on the following website: [https://www.bfdi.bund.de/DE/Infothek/Anschriften_Links/anschriften_links-node.html - as of May 2018].
§ 4 - Website and Logfiles
Each time our website is accessed, our system automatically collects data and information from the computer system of the calling computer. The following data is collected: (1) information about the browser type and the version used, (2) the user's operating system, (3) the user's Internet service provider, (4) the user's IP address, (5 ) Date and time of access, (6) websites from which the user's system accesses our website, (7) websites accessed by the user's system via our website.
The data is also stored in the log files of our system. A storage of this data together with other personal data of the user does not take place. The legal basis for the temporary storage of data and log files is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f DSGVO. The temporary storage of the IP address by the system is necessary to allow delivery of the website to the computer of the user. To do this, the user's IP address must be kept for the duration of the session.
Storage in log files is done to ensure the functionality of the website. In addition, the data is used to optimize the website and to ensure the security of our information technology systems. An evaluation of the data for marketing purposes does not take place in this context. For these purposes, our legitimate interest in the processing of data according to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f DSGVO. The data will be deleted as soon as it is no longer necessary for the purpose of its collection. In the case of collecting the data for providing the website, this is the case when the respective session is completed.
In the case of storing the data in log files, this is the case after no more than seven days. An additional storage is possible. In this case, the IP addresses of the users are deleted or alienated, so that an assignment of the calling client is no longer possible. The collection of data for the provision of the website and the storage of the data in log files is essential for the operation of the website. There is consequently no contradiction on the part of the user.
§ 5 - Cookies
Our website uses cookies. Cookies are text files that are stored in the Internet browser or the Internet browser on the user's computer system. When a user visits a website, a cookie may be stored on the user's operating system. This cookie contains a characteristic string that allows the browser to be uniquely identified when the website is reopened. We use cookies to make our website more user-friendly. Some elements of our website require that the calling browser be identified even after a page break. The following data is stored and transmitted in the cookies: language settings and log-in information.
The legal basis for the processing of personal data using cookies is Article 6 (1) lit. f DSGVO. The purpose of using technically necessary cookies is to facilitate the use of websites for users. Some features of our website can not be offered without the use of cookies. For these, it is necessary that the browser is recognized even after a page break. We require cookies for the following applications: (1) adopting language settings, (2) remembering search terms. The user data collected through technically necessary cookies will not be used to create user profiles. For these purposes, our legitimate interest in the processing of personal data pursuant to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f DSGVO.
Cookies are stored on the computer of the user and transmitted by this on our side. Therefore, as a user, you have full control over the use of cookies. By changing the settings in your internet browser, you can disable or restrict the transmission of cookies. Already saved cookies can be deleted at any time. This can also be done automatically. If cookies are disabled for our website, it may not be possible to use all the functions of the website to the full. The transmission of Flash cookies can not be prevented by the settings of the browser, but by changing the settings of the Flash Player.
§ 6 - Newsletter
On our website you can subscribe to a free newsletter. When registering for the newsletter, the following data will be sent to us: E-mail address of the user, IP address of the calling computer, date and time of registration. For the processing of the data, your consent is obtained during the registration process and reference is made to this privacy policy.
If you purchase goods or services on our website and deposit your e-mail address here, this can subsequently be used by us to send a newsletter. In such a case, the newsletter will only send direct mail for your own similar goods or services. In connection with the processing of data for the sending of newsletters, there is no disclosure of the data to third parties. The data will be used exclusively for sending the newsletter.
The legal basis for the processing of the data after the user has registered for the newsletter is the consent of the user Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR. The legal basis for sending the newsletter as a result of the sale of goods or services is § 7 Abs. 3 UWG. The collection of the user's e-mail address serves to deliver the newsletter. The collection of other personal data in the context of the registration process serves to prevent misuse of the services or the email address used.
The data will be deleted as soon as it is no longer necessary for the purpose of its collection. The e-mail address of the user is therefore stored as long as the subscription to the newsletter is active. The other personal data collected during the registration process will normally be deleted after a period of seven days. Subscription to the newsletter may be terminated at any time by the user concerned. For this purpose, there is a corresponding link in each newsletter. This also allows a revocation of the consent to the storage of the personal data collected during the registration process.
§ 7 - Registration
On our website, we offer users the opportunity to register by providing personal information. The data is entered into an input mask and transmitted to us and stored. A transfer of data to third parties does not take place. The following data is collected during the registration process: title, first name, surname, birth date if applicable, place of birth, company, department, address, phone, if necessary fax, e-mail, internet address if applicable.
At the time of registration, the following data is also stored: The IP address of the user, date and time of registration. As part of the registration process, the consent of the user to process this data is obtained. Legal basis for the processing of the data is in the presence of the consent of the user Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR. If the registration serves the fulfillment of a contract of which the user is a party or the implementation of pre-contractual measures, an additional legal basis for the processing of the data is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b DSGVO.
User registration is required for the provision of certain content and services on our website, such as password-protected areas for specific user groups. Registration of the user is also required to fulfill a contract with the user or to perform pre-contractual action - for example, membership, attendance, training and consulting.
The data will be deleted as soon as it is no longer necessary for the purpose of its collection. On the one hand, this is the case for the data collected during the registration process, when the registration on our website is canceled or modified. On the other hand, this is the case during the registration process for the performance of a contract or the performance of pre-contractual measures when the data is no longer necessary for the performance of the contract. Even after the conclusion of the contract, there may be a need to store personal data of the contracting party in order to comply with contractual or legal obligations.
As a user, you have the option of canceling the registration at any time. You can change the data stored about you at any time. Please contact the above mentioned office. If the data is required to fulfill a contract or to carry out pre-contractual measures, premature deletion of the data is only possible, unless contractual or legal obligations preclude deletion.
§ 8 - contact form and e-mail contact
On our website is a contact form available, which can be used for electronic contact. If a user realizes this option, the data entered in the input mask will be transmitted to us and saved. These data include: Title, first and last name, address, telephone, fax, e-mail, Internet address.
At the time of sending the message, the following data is also stored: (1) the user's IP address, (2) date and time of registration. For the processing of the data in the context of the sending process your consent is obtained and referred to this privacy statement. Alternatively, contact via the provided e-mail address is possible. In this case, the user's personal data transmitted by e-mail will be stored.
In this context, there is no disclosure of the data to third parties. The data is used exclusively for processing the conversation. Legal basis for the processing of the data is in the presence of the consent of the user Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a GDPR. The legal basis for the processing of the data transmitted in the course of sending an e-mail is Article 6 (1) lit. f DSGVO. If the e-mail contact aims to conclude a contract, then additional legal basis for the processing is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b DSGVO.
The processing of the personal data from the input mask serves us only to process the contact. In the case of contact via e-mail, this also includes the required legitimate interest in the processing of the data. The other personal data processed during the sending process serve to prevent misuse of the contact form and to ensure the security of our information technology systems.
The data will be deleted as soon as it is no longer necessary for the purpose of its collection. For the personal data from the input form of the contact form and those sent by e-mail, this is the case when the respective conversation with the user has ended. The conversation is ended when it can be inferred from the circumstances that the relevant facts have been finally clarified. The additional personal data collected during the sending process will be deleted at the latest after a period of seven days.
The user has the possibility at any time to revoke his consent to the processing of the personal data. If the user contacts us by e-mail, he may object to the storage of his personal data at any time. In such a case, the conversation can not continue. Please contact the above mentioned office for this purpose. All personal data stored in the course of contacting will be deleted in this case.
§ 9 - Google
We use Google Adwords Conversion Tracking to statistically track the use of our website. If the user has reached this website via an advertisement on Google, Google places a cookie on the user's computer. The cookie can not be used to personally identify users and will expire after 30 days. Google uses the cookies to generate conversion statistics. These tell Adwords customers how many people have been redirected to the site through the ad. Information for the personal identification of users is not included.
If users do not want to participate in the Google Adwords Conversion Tracking, you can set their browser individually so that cookies from the Internet address www.googleadservices.com are not accepted. Alternatively, the setting of cookies can be completely blocked by a corresponding browser setting. For more information about Google Adwords Conversion Tracking privacy, visit the following Internet address [https://services.google.com/sitestats/en.html - as of May 2018].
We use Google Analytics to obtain information for the continuous optimization of this website. For this purpose, Google places a cookie on the user's computer and creates usage profiles in pseudonymised form. The following information is collected by Google in connection with the cookie and stored on servers in the USA: Type and version of the browser, operating system used, URL of the previously visited page, IP address or host name of the accessing computer, date and time of the server request.
Google uses this information to compile reports on the use of the website in anonymous form for the purposes of market and usage research. The owner of the website is thus given the opportunity to make the website needs-based. Google also transmits this data to third parties, provided that they process the data in the order or the transfer is required by law. In the context of IP masking, the IP addresses are anonymized, so that an assignment of the data to specific persons is not possible.
If users so wish, they can prevent the placement of a cookie or the processing of the data collected by Google. For this purpose, you must either install the relevant browser add-on or set a temporary opt-out cookie by clicking on the website [https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en - as of May 2018]. However, the opt-out cookie in question only applies to the website in question only in the browser in question. If the cookie is deleted when closing the browser or manually, it must be reset. Alternatively, the setting of cookies can be completely blocked by a corresponding browser setting. Additional information on Google Analytics privacy can be found at the following Internet address [https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en - as of May 2018].
We integrate Google Maps as maps to give users a spatial orientation (eg for the journey). Google places a cookie on the user's computer in order to process the user settings in this way. Google processes the IP address of the user as well as his location data and stores them on servers in the USA.
Users who do not want Google to process and store this data can prevent this through individual settings on their mobile phone, notebook etc. For this purpose, the function "Java Script" must be deactivated in the browser. Then, however, no use of the maps is possible. More information on Google Maps privacy can be found on the following Internet address [https://www.google.com/intl/en_en/help/terms_maps.html - as of May 2018].
We use Google Fonts as fonts on the website to make the content visually appealing and technically sound. When you call the font library, your browser connects to the publisher of the font library. In doing so, the provider may collect your IP address and browser type and store that data on servers in the United States. The font library is also transferred to the cache of your browser so that it does not have to be loaded multiple times by the server.
Users who do not want to display using Google Fonts can opt-out from the following page: [https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated - as of May 2018]. Additional Google information on Google Fonts privacy can be found at the following Internet address [https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en - as of May 2018]. The company can be reached as follows (as of May 2018): Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA.§ 10 - Social Media Plug-ins
On our website, we use social plug-ins from the three social networks Facebook, Twitter and Google+. Integration uses the two-click method to best protect site users. The legal basis is Art. 6 para. 1 sentence 1 lit. f DSGVO and the purpose of advertising or publicizing our website in the social media. The legal responsibility for the operation according to the data protection regulations lies with the respective providers. You can reach the providers as follows (as of May 2018): Facebook, Inc., 1601 Willow Road, Menlo Park, CA 94025, USA, Twitter, Inc., 1355 Market Street, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, United States Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. When a user opens a website with a personalized social plug-in, the browser connects to the social network servers in the US and stores information there. This transmits the IP address and URL of the page in question to the networks. If the user is currently logged in to his social network account, the networks also assign the visit to the website directly to the relevant user account.
If the user interacts with the individually activated social plug-in (eg "Share", "Like"), this information is also transmitted to the servers of the social networks and stored there. The social networks also publish the information in the profile of the respective user or inform the respective friends, followers, etc. In addition, the social networks use the information for the purpose of their own page optimization and user profiling (eg in the display of matching advertisements).
If users wish to prevent their information from being passed on to the social networks or their activities on our site are linked to their user accounts, they must log out of their social network user accounts before visiting this site and participate in the social plug-in do not enable the two-click method.
We operate presences on the social networks Facebook, Twitter and Google+ to communicate information about our services and to interact with users. If users compose posts within our presence on the social networks or use them to send messages to us, we process them in accordance with this privacy policy. In addition, when calling and using the social networks, the data processing declarations of the respective operators apply.
As a provider of the website, we generally do not receive any information about the content of the data transmitted to the social networks or the further use by the social networks. For information on the extent and purpose of data collection, data processing and data use by the social networks, users should therefore read the relevant data protection notice of Facebook [https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy - as of May 2018], Twitter [ https://twitter.com/privacy - as of May 2018] and Google [https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en - as of May 2018].
§ 11 - Amazon
We are affiliates of Amazon Affiliate Program. By making links from this website to Amazon.de, advertising reimbursements are earned. This serves the purpose of enabling us to economically operate the website. Amazon places cookies on the computer of the user. This will allow Amazon to tell which website from which IP address which link was clicked, and then possibly purchase a product from Amazon. Users who do not want this data transmission to Amazon can prevent this by not clicking on the relevant link to Amazon.de. Further information from Amazon on privacy can be found at the following Internet address [https://www.amazon.de/gp/help/customer/display.html?nodeId=3312401 - as of May 2018]. The company can be reached as follows: Amazon Europe Core S.à.rl, 5 Rue Plaetis, L-2338 Luxembourg.§ 12 - Applicants
Applicants will provide us with necessary data for the application process. The data transmitted here result from the job description. This usually includes personal information (eg contact addresses), motivation (eg cover letter) and previous career (eg CV, certificates). Applicants are free to submit further information. If the applicant submits special categories of personal data (eg, severe disability), the data processing is additionally carried out in accordance with Art. 9 (2) lit. b DSGVO.
The information provided by the applicant is intended to enable us to fulfill our obligations under the application procedure. Data collection and data processing are carried out in accordance with Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b. DSGVO and Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f. DSGVO and the use of the transmitted data exclusively in the context of the application process. When submitting by e-mail, the applicant himself has to provide adequate encryption. If this is not possible for him, he can submit the application by post.
If the application was successful, the data submitted by the applicant will be further processed and stored for the purposes of administration and billing of the employment relationship. If the application was unsuccessful or the application is withdrawn by the applicant, the data submitted by the applicant will be deleted. The time of deletion results from the proof duties of the general equal treatment law (AGG), is usually six months and is subject to a possibly justified cancellation of the applicants.
§ 13 - Customers or members
Via the website persons can conclude legally valid contracts for the use of paid services (eg attendance of events, membership in associations). For this purpose, the collection and processing of personal data of the contracting party in accordance with Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b DSGVO or Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f. DSGVO necessary (eg, first and last name, postal address, e-mail address, telephone number, services used, payment information). The IP address as well as the date and time of the conclusion of the contract by the user are also stored.
The purpose of the processing is the administration, provision and billing of corresponding services as well as the maintenance of our business operations. In part, the processing and storage of personal data is also based on statutory provisions (eg tax law), contractual provisions (eg delivery address, performance variant) or security reasons (eg to verify the ownership of e-mail addresses, seriousness of the desired receipt of service, accuracy the billing address).
A transfer of these data to third parties does not take place, as long as no legal obligation according to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. c DSGVO exists or this is necessary for the performance or enforcement of our claims. The data will be deleted as soon as they are no longer required for business or statutory purposes. The deletion point results from the legal storage obligations as well as from warranty or liability regulations. The need for further data storage is reviewed every three years.
§ 14 - Status and necessary changes
This Privacy Policy was created in May 2018. Due to the further development of our website and the further development of the law, changes to the privacy policy may become necessary. You will find the currently valid privacy policy here.
© 2000-2020 Crisisnavigator - Institute for Crisis Research / Crisisnavigator Consulting, Kiel. All rights reserved. No unauthorised reproduction or distribution - not even in extracts. ISSN 1619-2400. Internet: www.crisisnavigator.com  | E-Mail: roselieb@crisisnavigator.com
About us
OverviewEmergency CallMediaNewsletterContactPrivacyImprintSitemapSearch
Crisis InformationCrisis ManagementCrisis CommunicationsIssues ManagementDisaster ManagementBusiness ContinuityContactCrisis ResearchOverviewContactCrisis ConsultingOverviewCrisis PreventionCrisis IdentificationCrisis ManagementCrisis RecoveryContactCrisis TrainingOverviewContactAbout usOverviewEmergency CallMediaNewsletterContactPrivacyImprintSitemapSearch
German
/  English
Last update: Friday, 11. December 2020
Crisis competence for long-term success.
